Jeremy Crichton

★ jeremycrichton.com ☑ jeremy@jeremycrichton.com ☑ JeremyCrichton

♥ Vancouver, BC, Canada

Profile

I'm a software engineer with experience developing fast, scalable cloud applications. I recently built Jade, a framework for deploying JAMstack applications on AWS infrastructure. I'm also a Canadian CPA with extensive experience in financial reporting and corporate finance.

Professional Experience

Co-Creator, Software Engineer

2020 - present

jadeframework.dev

Open source framework for deploying JAMstack apps to AWS that abstracts away the time and complexity of provisioning cloud resources and writing backend code

- Reduced provisioning and configuration of underlying AWS infrastructure (S3, Cloudfront, EC2, Lambda, DyanmoDB and IAM) to a single CLI command
- Built a Node.js app running on EC2 to handle continuous build and deployment processes of apps
- Utilized Docker to isolate individual application build environments in EC2
- Designed and built a responsive UI dashboard with React, Node.js and Express as well as a Node.js CLI
- Collaborated daily with remote engineers across 3 time zones
- Co-authored and built case study website with Gatsby.js and deployed with Jade: jadeframework.dev

Full Stack Web Developer

2018 - 2020

Papersword B2B Marketing and Self Employed

- Built web applications, custom Wordpress templates and marketing websites
- Developed open-source software including:
 - Photoblog: A photo sharing app built with React, Node, Express, MongoDB and authentication with JWTs
 - Reaction: A project manager inspired by Trello, built with React and Rails
 - Postit: A Reddit-like application built with Rails

Vice President, Corporate Finance

2009 - 2016

Fiore Management & Advisory Corp.

• CFO of several publicly listed companies responsible for financial reporting and continuous disclosure as well as advising and reporting on numerous corporate restructurings and financing transactions

Skills

Languages & frameworks

Cloud

Other

Javascript (ES6+), Node.js, Express, React, Redux, Ruby, Rails, SQL, MongoDB AWS (IAM, EC2, Lambda, DynamoDB S3, Cloudfront), Digital Ocean, Heroku Docker, REST and GraphQL APIs, Apollo, Git, Github

Education

Software Engineering, Web Development

2018 – 2020 | Remote

Launch School, launchschool.com/employers ☑

A rigorous program building strong fundamentals in software engineering utilizing mastery-based learning.

Chartered Professional Accountant

2008 | Canada

CA School of Business

Bachelor of Commerce

2004 | Victoria, Canada

University of Victoria